<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tunisia on Christopher Barrie</title>
    <link>/categories/tunisia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tunisia on Christopher Barrie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Christopher Barrie 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/tunisia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Younger electorates vote independent in Tunisian Municipal Elections</title>
      <link>/post/bpost05222018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bpost05222018/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Municipalities with a greater number of younger registered voters saw a higher vote share for independent lists. Similarly, younger electorates were less likely to vote for established parties.
Introduction On May 6, Tunisia held its first municipal elections since the 2011 Revolution. In a previous post, I showed that younger municipalities and municipalities with more political competition/electoral mobilization saw higher turnout. In this post, I look at associations between municipality-level demographics and voting patterns again but focus on the the types of parties that were successful in each municipality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth and competition boost turnout in Tunisian Municipal Elections</title>
      <link>/post/bpost18062018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bpost18062018/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Municipalities with a greater number of younger registered voters experienced higher turnout. Municipalities with more candidates proportional to the size of the electorate witnessed substantially increased turnout.
Introduction On May 6, Tunisia held its first municipal elections since the 2011 Revolution. While the country has now witnessed two rounds of free and fair national elections, municipal elections have been subject to multiple delays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Tunisian Revolution</title>
      <link>/post/bpost05062018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bpost05062018/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR You can make hexmaps easily from a shapefile with the geogrid package in R. To sort out the geography for shapefiles with polygons of highly variant sizes, there is a workaround I found with the cartogram package.
 Introduction R provides a growing number of mapping packages. In this post I document my workflow for producing a map of the diffusion of protest during the Tunisian Revolution. The following packages will be required for anyone who has similar mapping requirements and wishes to follow the same steps:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>